<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Andrew Murray</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Andrew Murray</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatting eosense &amp; Vaisala data with R</title>
      <link>/post/formatting-eosense_vaisala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/formatting-eosense_vaisala/</guid>
      <description>Formatting CO2 Data for Use in R  In this post I will describe my workflow for formatting CO2 Data for use within R statistical software. CO2 data was collected using two sensors, a Vaisalla GNP-222 and and eosense eosFD Soil CO2 Flux Sensor. While these are the sensors I use, the workflow should be similar regardless of the sensor. The Vaisala collects CO2 readings only. The eosense collects CO2, CO2 Flux, and temperature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NC State Fair</title>
      <link>/post/nc-state-fair/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nc-state-fair/</guid>
      <description>NC State Fair Attendance  Check out this interactive plot on NC State Fair Attendance by day of the fair and colored by year. I have been playing around with plotly visualizations and in the spirit of the North Carolina State Fair, wanted to show how the attendance changes by day of the fair and through the years. The code I used to create this plot can be found below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domestic Wells and Fracking:</title>
      <link>/project/domestic-wells-and-fracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/domestic-wells-and-fracking/</guid>
      <description>Methane Contamination of Wells In recent years, the practice of hydraulic fracturing has raised concerns among those who obtain domestic water for home use from privately owned wells in areas that have been experienceing development of unconventional natural gas extraction (fracking) activities. This is a living document of my research investigating the potential risk to private wells from contamination relating to fracking throughout the United States. The goal of this document is for it to be submitted as a manuscript once it is completed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Flux</title>
      <link>/project/carbon-flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/carbon-flux/</guid>
      <description>What is Carbon Flux? When we refer to the carbon cycle, we are talking about how carbon moves through the different parts of the earth system. Carbon can be transported to and from different parts of the earth system in several different ways such as the burning of fossil fuels, plant respiration, photosynthesis, and soil decomposition to name a few. When we talk about carbon flux we are talking about understanding how much carbon moves between sources and sinks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deal Me In</title>
      <link>/project/deal-me-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/deal-me-in/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
When you click the Knit button a document will be generated that includes both content as well as the output of any embedded R code chunks within the document. You can embed an R code chunk like this:
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>