<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Andrew Murray</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Andrew Murray</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Domestic Wells and Fracking:</title>
      <link>/project/domestic-wells-and-fracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/domestic-wells-and-fracking/</guid>
      <description>Methane Contamination of Wells In recent years, the practice of hydraulic fracturing has raised concerns among those who obtain domestic water for home use from privately owned wells in areas that have been experienceing development of unconventional natural gas extraction (fracking) activities. This is a living document of my research investigating the potential risk to private wells from contamination relating to fracking throughout the United States. The goal of this document is for it to be submitted as a manuscript once it is completed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Flux</title>
      <link>/project/carbon-flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/carbon-flux/</guid>
      <description>What is Carbon Flux? When we refer to the carbon cycle, we are talking about how carbon moves through the different parts of the earth system. Carbon can be transported to and from different parts of the earth system in several different ways such as the burning of fossil fuels, plant respiration, photosynthesis, and soil decomposition to name a few. When we talk about carbon flux we are talking about understanding how much carbon moves between sources and sinks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>